sorensonmedia.com 2015-05-26

# Privacy | Sorenson Media

## Sorenson Media, Inc. Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy and Agreement (“Privacy Policy”) will tell you what information Sorenson Media, Inc. (“Sorenson Media”) collects about you and about your use of Sorenson Media’s website. It will explain how Sorenson Media protects that information and what choices you have about how it is used. Sorenson Media urges you to read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you will understand clearly how Sorenson Media may collect and use information provided by you because, by using the Sorenson Media website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Sorenson Media will inform you of the following in this privacy policy:**

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected;
  * What organization is collecting the information;
  * How the information is used;
  * With whom the information may be shared;
  * What choices are available regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information;
  * What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under Sorenson Media’s control; and, how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

Please remember that any information (including information of a financial and/or other personal nature) that you reveal in a Sorenson Media public forum (such as a bulletin board, posting, chat room/event) is not protected by this Privacy Policy and that such postings will be seen by third parties not related to Sorenson Media. Also, what you’ve written in a Sorenson Media public forum could be used by others in ways Sorenson Media is unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes. Also, if you access a third party site from a link on Sorenson Media, please be aware that any information you reveal on that site is not subject to this Privacy Policy and, therefore, you should consult the privacy policies of each site you visit.

**I. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY SORENSON MEDIA OR ON SORENSON MEDIA’S BEHALF.**

**A. In General**

Personally Identifiable Information (PII or Personal Information) is information that can be used to identify or contact you. Sorenson Media collects the Personal Information that you provide to us in two general and distinct ways: (1) when you choose to purchase various services or products offered by Sorenson Media and/or its affiliated business partners, or (2) when you choose to participate in surveys or send e-mails to Sorenson Media. Sorenson Media also collects non-personal information from you and about your use of its website, e-mails, special promotions and newsletters that Sorenson Media may send to you, and websites of selected sponsors and advertisers. To no longer receive e-mails or other electronic communications from Sorenson Media, you must elect to opt-out.

**B. Registration And Other Information.**

You may view or use Sorenson Media’s website without registering or submitting any Personal Information. In that case, the only information Sorenson Media collects will be non-personal information collected through the use of cookies or web beacons (see details below).

However, in order to have access to certain products and services available on Sorenson Media’s website, you are required to complete a registration form and provide other information reasonably necessary for us to provide the products and/or services for you. Some examples of the information Sorenson Media collects in the Registration form are:

  * Your Name
  * Your Address(es)
  * Your Phone Number(s)
  * Your E-mail Address(es)
  * Your Login Name
  * Your Password
  * Pages Viewed
  * Your Credit Card Number(s)
  * Your Customers’ IP Address(es)
  * Your Operating System/Machine Type

**C. Cookies**

Sorenson Media also collects anonymous, non-confidential, and non-personal information when you use its site, send it e-mails, or respond to special promotions or newsletters that Sorenson Media may send to you from time to time. For example, cookies are small computer files that Sorenson Media transfers to your computer’s hard drive that allow us to know how often someone visits a site and the activities they conduct while on that site (such as the chatrooms you visited, whether you submitted orders for services or products, etc.). Every computer is assigned a different cookie by Sorenson Media. The information collected by cookies helps us dynamically generate advertising and content on web pages or in e-mails specifically designed for you and also allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using Sorenson Media’s site and selected affiliated business partners sites, or are opening Sorenson Media’s e-mails. Sorenson Media may use cookie information to target certain advertisements to your browser or to determine the popularity of certain content or advertisements. It may be possible to link non-personal cookie information to Personal Information collected.

**D. Web Beacons**

In limited circumstances Sorenson Media also may use “web beacons” to collect anonymous, non-personal information about your use of its website and the sites of selected affiliated partners, and your use of e-mails, special promotions or newsletters Sorenson Media may send to you from time to time. Web beacons are tiny graphic image files imbedded in a web page or e-mail that provide a presence on the web page or e-mail and send back to its home server information from the Users’ browser. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using Sorenson Media’s site and selected affiliated business partners sites, or are opening its e-mails, and for what purposes. It may be possible to link non-personal web beacon information to Personal Information collected.

**E. E-mails and Newsletters**

As noted in the discussions of cookies and web beacons (see above), Sorenson Media collects anonymous, non-personal information about your use of e-mails and newsletters that Sorenson Media may send to you from time to time. In some cases, when you click on a link or an advertisement in an e-mail or newsletter, your browser may be momentarily directed to the site of a third party which, acting on Sorenson Media’s behalf (see Disclosure to Website Service and Content Contractors, below), notes or “counts” your response to the e-mail or newsletter before re-directing your browser to its proper destination. This re-direction process will not be apparent to you.

**F. Information Collected by Third Parties Not Acting on Sorenson Media’s Behalf.**

Sponsors, business partners or advertisers on the Sorenson Media’s site or in e-mails, special promotions or newsletters Sorenson Media may send to you from time to time may also use their own cookies or web beacons when you click on their advertisement or link to their site or service, or even if the advertisement simply appears on a page or in an e-mail that you are viewing. Some advertisers use companies other than Sorenson Media to serve their ads and to monitor users’ responses to ads, and these companies (“Ad Servers”) may also collect non-personal information through the use of cookies or web beacons on Sorenson Media’s website. In certain situations, information collection may be facilitated by momentarily directing your browser to the site of an Ad Server or other third party acting on behalf of the sponsor, business partner, or advertiser before re-directing your browser to its proper destination (e.g., back to Sorenson Media to show the ad, or to the advertiser’s website); this re-direction process will not be apparent to you.

Sorenson Media does not control these third parties’ use of cookies or web beacons, or how they manage the non-personal information they gather through them. However, Sorenson Media does require sponsors, advertisers and Ad Servers who collect cookie or web beacon information through Sorenson Media’s website to agree that they will not collect any Personal Information from its site without your consent. They have promised us they will not link any non-personal cookie or web beacon information collected by them on Sorenson Media’s site to Personal Information they or others collect in other ways or from other sites. However, you should review the privacy policy of other sites you visit or link to from Sorenson Media’s site to understand how these other sites use cookies and how they use the information they collect through the use of cookies or web beacons on their own sites.

**G. Public Forums**

This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you use Sorenson Media’s public forums if and when they become available. As a service to Sorenson Media’s users, Sorenson Media may feature chat rooms and bulletin boards where users can share information and support one another or where users can post questions for other users to answer. You should be aware that any information shared in a chat room, bulletin board, or other type of posting is public information and may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties that do not adhere to Sorenson Media’s Privacy Policy. You should think carefully before disclosing any personal information in any public forum.

**H. E-mails to Sorenson Media**

This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you send business information, resumes, ideas, concepts or inventions to Sorenson Media by e-mail to the various Sorenson Media’s departments listed on the Sorenson Media’s website. If you want to keep business information, resumes, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an e-mail to Sorenson Media. Sorenson Media tries to answer every e-mail in a timely manner, but are not always able to do so.

**II. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION.**

A. Except as set forth in this paragraph II, or as specifically agreed to by you, Sorenson Media will not use, disclose, or store any Personal Information it gathers from you on its website unless reasonably required in order to answer your questions, to provide products and/or services you may request or purchase from its website (such as, information Sorenson Media needs to share with its credit card internet gateway), or unless reasonably required in order to comply with a governmental or Sorenson Media company record-keeping requirement.

Sorenson Media may release Personal Information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as a financial threat to you or others. In the event that Sorenson Media is legally compelled to disclose your Personal Information to a third party, Sorenson Media will notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order.

**B. Disclosure to Sorenson Media’s Subsidiaries/Affiliated Entities.**

Sorenson Media may disclose Personal Information to its corporate subsidiaries or entities affiliated with Sorenson Media. Any Personal Information provided to Sorenson Media’s subsidiaries or entities affiliated with Sorenson Media will be treated by those subsidiaries and affiliated entities in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**C. Disclosure to Sorenson Media’s Operations and Maintenance Contractors**

Sorenson Media’s operations and maintenance contractors may sometimes have limited access to your Personal Information in the course of providing products or services to Sorenson Media. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of Sorenson Media’s website. These contractors also may have access to your e-mail address to send newsletters or special promotions to you on Sorenson Media’s behalf or to send e-mails to you for purposes such as conducting market research on Sorenson Media’s behalf. Access to your Personal Information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for the contractor to perform its limited function for Sorenson Media. Sorenson Media also contractually requires that its operations and maintenance contractors (1) protect the privacy of your Personal Information, and (2) not use or disclose your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services.

**D. Disclosure to Website Service and Content Contractors**

Certain content and products and services offered to you through Sorenson Media’s website are served on websites hosted and operated by a company other than Sorenson Media (“Third Party Contractor Websites”). Therefore, if you purchase services or products through one of these Third Party Contractor Websites, you will be purchasing it from the Third Party Contractor and not from Sorenson Media. Further, you should be aware that any information you disclose once you access these other sites is not subject to this Privacy Policy. Sorenson Media does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Contractor Websites and, therefore, you should review the privacy policy posted on the other site to understand how that Third Party Contractor Website collects and uses your Personal Information. Also, if you have reason to believe that you may be leaving Sorenson Media’s website and entering a Third Party Contractor Website, you should be cautious about providing any personal information until you have reviewed the privacy policy posted on the other site.

**E. Disclosure To Or By Co-branded Channel Partners**

Sorenson Media is a contractor and provides co-branded products and/or services to websites hosted and operated by companies other than Sorenson Media (“Channel Partner Websites”). You can only access these co-branded content and products and/or services through the Channel Partner Website. The co-branded Sorenson Media pages that you may access through a Channel Partner Website have different registration processes and opportunities for information collection, and Personal Information that you provide on these pages may be shared with the Channel Partners. Each of these co-branded Sorenson Media sites has its own privacy policy posted on that site. Therefore, if you visit one of these co-branded Sorenson Media sites, please read the privacy policy that is posted on that site, as well as the individual privacy policy of the Channel Partner Website.

**F. Disclosure to Linked Sites**

In addition to the Third Party Contractor Websites that you may access as described above, for your convenience there are links to websites operated by companies other than Sorenson Media (“Third Party Websites”) that are not contractors who provide content, products, and/or services through Sorenson Media’s website. These links may be found in advertisements, referenced within content, or placed beside the names or logos of sponsors or affiliated business partners of Sorenson Media. Sorenson Media does not disclose your Personal Information to these Third Party Websites without obtaining your consent. Sorenson Media does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these sites. If you choose to link to one of these Third Party Websites, you should review the privacy policy posted on this other site to understand how that Third Party Website collects and uses your Personal Information.

**G. Disclosure of Aggregate Information**

Sorenson Media may provide to third parties non-personal information about you that does not allow you to be identified or contacted and that is combined with the non-personal information of other users (“Aggregate Information”). For example, Sorenson Media might inform third parties regarding the number of users of its site and the activities they conduct while on its site. Sorenson Media might also inform a company that performs services or that provides products and/or services to Sorenson Media (that may or may not be a Sorenson Media business partner or an advertiser on its site) that “50% of Sorenson Media’s users live in the USA” or that “85% of Sorenson Media’s users have purchased products and/or services which can be downloaded from Sorenson Media’s website.” Depending on the circumstances, Sorenson Media may or may not charge third parties for this Aggregate Information. Sorenson Media also may not limit the third parties’ use of the Aggregate Information, except that Sorenson Media does require third parties to whom Sorenson Media discloses Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable by combining it with other databases or otherwise.

**III. HOW SORENSON MEDIA HANDLES PRIVACY AND SECURITY INTERNALLY.**

Sorenson Media wants your Personal Information to remain as secure as possible. That is why Sorenson Media has a two-tier security system at Sorenson Media that combines leading technical safeguards and a code of conduct for those personnel who are permitted to access its customers’ Personal Information. On the technical side, Sorenson Media uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology in transmitting your Personal Information to Sorenson Media’s servers to help ensure the integrity and privacy of the Personal Information you provide to us via the Internet. Encryption involves systematically scrambling numbers and letters, so that even if someone managed to intercept the information, they would not be able to make sense of it. In order to take advantage of this encryption technology, you need to have an Internet browser that will support 128-bit encryption, such as Netscape or Microsoft Explorer. As an additional security measure, your Personal Information is also kept physically separate on a separate server where your password is encrypted and stored on a database. On the personnel side, only a limited number of Sorenson Media personnel are authorized to access your Personal Information. All Sorenson Media personnel must abide by Sorenson Media’s Privacy Policy and those who violate Sorenson Media’s Privacy Policy are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination. Although Sorenson Media will make every reasonable effort to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that thieves could find a way to thwart Sorenson Media’s security systems.

**IV. YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES.**

When you complete Registration, you will be given the option of receiving recurring informational/promotional e-mails from Sorenson Media and/or third parties. You may opt out of receiving e-mails from or on behalf of Sorenson Media at Registration by removing the automatic check mark from the statement that expresses a preference for receiving these e-mails and newsletters. You may also opt out of receiving these e-mails and newsletters at any time. When you have received a newsletter you wish to stop, click on the “reply” button in your mail program, then type in the word “UNSUBSCRIBE” in the “Subject” field and send. Sorenson Media’s Customer Service will unsubscribe you.

At Registration, you may also have the option of receiving e-mails or newsletters from third parties, participating in research or marketing surveys and participating in other activities. You may exercise these options by placing a check mark beside a statement that expresses a preference for receiving these communications or participating in these activities. You may change your decision at any time by following the directions regarding how to unsubscribe from these e-mails or newsletters.

This privacy statement applies only to the Sorenson Media’s website. The Sorenson Media website does contain links to other sites. Once you enter another website (whether through an advertisement, service, or content link), be aware that Sorenson Media is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Sorenson Media encourages you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit through a link or advertisement on Sorenson Media’s website or any site that collects Personal Information from you.

**V. UPDATING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND CONTACTING SORENSON MEDIA.**

You can always contact us in order to (1) delete your Personal Information from Sorenson Media’s systems, (2) update the Personal Information that you have provided to us, and (3) change your preferences with respect to marketing contacts or other activities, by e-mailing us at support@sorensonmedia.com. Such changes will not have any effect on other information that Sorenson Media maintains. If you have a complaint or problem you may e-mail us at support@sorensonmedia.com and the customer service department will forward your complaint to the appropriate internal Sorenson Media department for a response or resolution. Sorenson Media tries to answer every e-mail in a timely manner but are not always able to do so.

You should be aware that it may not be technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to Sorenson Media from its servers. The need to back-up Sorenson Media’s systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your Personal Information may exist in a non-erasable form that may be difficult or impossible for us to locate. Nevertheless, upon receiving your request, Sorenson Media will endeavor to delete all Personal Information stored in the databases Sorenson Media actively uses for research and daily business activities, as well as other readily searchable media.

Privacy as it applies to the Internet is a dynamic, rapidly developing area. Therefore, in the future, Sorenson Media may make significant changes to its privacy policy affecting the use of the Personal Information you provide to us. Therefore, you need to ensure that you visit Sorenson Media’s website from time to time and read its Privacy Policy in effect to see if Sorenson Media has made any significant changes concerning its use of your Personal Information.

Sorenson Media may also make non-significant changes to its Privacy Policy that generally will not affect its use of your Personal Information and, therefore, you should also check Sorenson Media’s posted Privacy Policy for any non-significant changes. Further, if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy, you should exit the site immediately.

© 2014 Sorenson Media, Inc. All rights reserved
